# Carlos E Sierra

web design+front end development+visual design



#### hello!

My name is Carlos Sierra, I'm a web designer and front-end developer based in Melbourne, Australia. I am into clean, cross-browser and usability oriented design and front end development which goes with the latest web standards and world wide trends.

I have over 9 years experience in the web industry and I have worked on multiple and diverse projects; as a result gaining strong skills in the IT field and passion for all things digital.

I do web and visual design, front end development, email design and development (eDM), UI development, XHTML/ HTML5 + CSS2/CSS3 valid coding, Javascript, Jquery, Wordpress themes, Magento themes, search engine optimization (SEO), responsive web design, logos, corporate identity and other graphic work.

## professional experience

Jetstar

Front End Developer (contract)

Aug 2016 - Sep 2017

- Web & Visual Design . Front End Development
- Responsive eDM Design & Development . Front End Development . Sitecore. Responsys.

Open Universities Australia (contract) eDM Developer

Nov 2015 - May 2016

- Web & Visual Design . Front End Development
- Responsive eDM Design & Development . Front End Development . Marketing Cloud.

Myer

Front End Developer (contract)

Oct 2015 - Nov 2015

- Web & Visual Design . Front End Development
- Responsive eDM Design & Development . Front End Development . Marketing Cloud.

DT Digital

Experience Designer (freelance)

Jun 2015 - Oct 2015

- eDM Development . Visual Design
- XHTML . CSS . Responsive eDM Development

XN Australia Pty Limited
Web Design & Development Manager

Jun 2014 - Dec 2014

- Web & Graphic Design . Front End Development
- XHTML . CSS . Responsive Design . Email Design

La Clinica For Skin And Body Web Designer & Front End Developer Dec 2012 - Jun2014

- Web Design . Front End Development
- Magento . Joomla . Virtuemart . PHP . XHTML . CSS

### skills

Web design / Web development

 XHTML/HTML5 . CSS2/CSS3 . JavaScript . Jquery . PHP . Adobe Dreamweaver . Sublime

Content management systems

Wordpress . Magento

E-commerce systems

Woocommerce . Magento

Edm testing and deployment

• Litmus . Email On Acid . Mailchimp

Digital graphics editing

• Adobe Photoshop . Adobe Photoshop Lightroom

Digital graphics design

Adobe Illustrator

Multimedia design

• Adobe After Effects . Adobe Premiere

Digital formatting and layout

Adobe InDesign

## Carlos E Sierra

web design+front end development+visual design



## education

Diploma of interactive digital media Western Institute of Technology Melbourne, Australia 2013

Flash Swinburne University of Technology Melbourne, Australia 2010

Web page development National Institute for Educational Cooperation (INCE) Maracaibo, Venezuela 2006

Correspondent Juventud Rebelde Newspaper Havana, Cuba 2006

Graphic design Maracaibo Municipal Office Maracaibo, Venezuela. 2005

Project development Center for Auditory Studies Zulia Maracaibo, Venezuela 2004

Installation of software, networks and periferals Universidad de Ciencias Informáticas UCI. La Habana, Cuba. 2004

Social work University of La Habana La Habana, Cuba 2004

Bachelor of arts-major in philosophy University of Zulia 5 semesters completed

## projects

- cartelelectrics.com.au
- hearourpain.com.au
- 3darchitectmelbourne.com.au
- mistertiler.com
- psychotherapymelbourne.com.au
- fotoartevideo.com
- turtlefilms.net
- soiltestsouthmelbourne.com.au
- carlosesierra.com.au
- earthworkercooperative.com.au
- soiltestmelbourne.com.au
- halfworldptyltd.com.au
- macelebrant.com

## in association with innovative growth solutions

- globaltrackaustralia.com.au
- lesterfranks.com.au

#### as a freelancer on DT Digital

- eDM development for officeworks.com.au
- Front end development for kmart.com.au
- Visual design for vintagecellars.com.au

### contact

Carlos E Sierra

Address: 204/14-20 Nicholson St Coburg VIC 3058

Phone: 0411386882

Email: carlosesierra@gmail.com Web: www.carlosesierra.com.au Residency status: Australian Citizen

#### references

Jennifer Mullins Senior Designer Jetstar

Tel: 8628 3157 | Email: jennifer.mullins@jetstar.com

Craig Chait

Senior Vice President of Sales and Marketing

XN Australia Pty Limited

Tel: 95250525 | Email: cchait@xnhotelsystems.com